<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathy Calzone on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/kathy-calzone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kathy Calzone on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/kathy-calzone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Counseling Strategies for Patients With a Germline Variant Downgraded to Uncertain Significance, Likely Benign or Benign Following Risk-Reducing Surgery</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-15/</guid>
      <description>Yi Liu, Grace-Ann Fasaye, Chimene Kesserwan, Kathleen Calzone
 Submitter: Yi Liu (Research nurse, genetic counselor) email: yi.liu2@nih.gov  Genetic variant interpretation is an evolving process dependent on the collective evidence at that moment of time. Also, it is based on the pipeline and expertise used in each laboratory despite the adoption of ACMG guidelines for sequence variant interpretation and centralized resources such as ClinVar. Thus, there is discordance in variant interpretation between laboratories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Between CDH1 Pathogenic and Likely Pathogenic Variants, Orofacial Cleft, and Cancer History </title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-16/</guid>
      <description>Anna Duemler, Grace-Ann Fasaye, Kathleen Calzone, Jeremy Davis Center for Cancer Research, National Cancer Institute (NCI), National Institutes of Health
 Submitter: Anna Duemler (Student or postbac) email: anna.duemler@nih.gov  Introduction: The CDH1 gene codes for epithelial cadherin protein(E-cadherin) production which is involved in calcium dependent cell adhesion and protein interactions for normal craniofacial development and tumor suppression. CDH1 pathogenic and likely pathogenic (P/LP) variants are associated with non-syndromic cleft lip and/or palate(CL/P); Blepharocheilodontic syndrome(characterized by eyelid malformations, CL/P and ectodermal dysplasia); Hereditary Diffuse Gastric Cancer(HDGC); and Hereditary Lobular Breast Cancer (HLBC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadening Our Knowledge of the BAP1 Tumor Predisposition Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-17/</guid>
      <description>Alexandra Lebensohn, Grace Fasaye, Maria Gracia Agra, Yvonne Mallory, Cathy Wagner, Rosemary Bekker, Azam Ghafoor, Kathleen Calzone, Raffit Hassan
 Submitter: Alexandra Lebensohn (Research nurse, genetic counselor) email: alexandra.lebensohn@nih.gov  There is still much to learn about hereditary malignant mesothelioma, historically attributed primarily to asbestos exposure. Hassan et al. demonstrated that germline DNA repair pathogenic variants are present in approximately 12% of malignant mesothelioma cases in a cohort of 385 patients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>