<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javed Khan on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/javed-khan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javed Khan on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/javed-khan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased Leukemic Epigenetic Plasticity and Pre-Treatment T-Cell Activation Predict Resistance to CD19 CAR T Cell Therapy in Pediatric Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-4/</guid>
      <description>Katherine E. Masih, David Milewski, Abdalla Abdelmaksoud, Hsien-Chao Chou, Berkley E. Gryder, Rebecca Gardner, Ashley L. Wilson, Serifat Adebola, Benjamin Z. Stanton, Young K. Song, Chaoyu Wang, Xinyu Wen, Zachary Rae, Allison Ruchinskas, Adam Cheuk, Grégoire Altan-Bonnet, Michael Kelly, Jun S. Wei, Michael C. Jensen, Rimas J. Orentas, and Javed Khan
 Submitter: Katherine E. Masih (Student or postbac) email: katherine.masih@nih.gov  Background Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) is the most common childhood cancer with a peak incidence between 3-5 years of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunogenomic Approaches to Optimize Immunotherapeutic Targeting of Neuroblastoma</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-5/</guid>
      <description>Meijie Tian, Adam Tai-Chi Cheuk, Jun S. Wei, Young K. Song, Abdalla Abdelmaksoud, Sivasish Sindiri, Nan Li, Christopher M. Dower, Haiying Qin, Mitchell Ho, Bradley St Croix, and Javed Khan
 Submitter: Meijie Tian (Postdoc or fellow) email: meijie.tian@nih.gov  Background: Neuroblastoma (NB) is the most common extra-cranial solid cancer in children. Although multimodal therapies with differentiating agents and immunotherapy with anti-GD2 antibody and GM-CSF have shown promising results, it remains deadly in approximately 50% of patients with high-risk disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined Immunogenomic and Immunopeptidomic Analyses Identified Biologically Relevant Immune Signatures and Novel Immunotherapy Targets in Osteosarcoma</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-6/</guid>
      <description>David Milewski, Jun S. Wei, Sivasish Sindiri, Andrew Brohl, Young Song, Xinyu Wen, Andy Qi, Udayan Guha, and Javed Khan.
 Submitter: David Milewski (Postdoc or fellow) email: david.milewski@nih.gov  Background: Osteosarcoma is an aggressive bone tumor that is one of the leading causes of cancer-related death in the pediatric population. Several phase I clinical trials have reported occasional clinical responses to immune checkpoint inhibitors in osteosarcoma patients. The key feature of immunotherapy involves T cell recognition of peptides from abnormal proteins (tumor-associated antigens; TAAs) presented by MHC class I of tumor cells which stimulates specific anti-tumor cytotoxicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a First-in-Class KDM3B Inhibitor That Suppresses PAX3-FOXO1 Oncogene Activity in Fusion Positive Rhabdomyosarcoma</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-7/</guid>
      <description>Yong Yean Kim, Robert Hawley, Berkley Gryder, Silvia Pomella, Josh Kowalczyk, Ranu Sinniah, Young Song, and Javed Khan
 Submitter: Yong Yean Kim (Postdoc or fellow) email: yong.kim@nih.gov  BACKGROUND: The PAX3/7-FOXO1 fusion gene is the major oncogenic driver in fusion positive rhabdomyosarcoma (FP-RMS), which is a highly aggressive soft tissue muscle sarcoma of childhood. The chimeric gene results from either t(2;13) or t(1;13) translocation and has been shown by our group to drive FP-RMS oncogenesis through transcription activation driven by super enhancers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>