<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Aplan on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/peter-aplan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peter Aplan on Genetics Branch Retreat 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/tags/peter-aplan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Renewal of Committed Hematopoietic Precursors Leads to Abnormal Hematopoiesis and Myelodysplastic Syndrome </title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-21/</guid>
      <description>Yang Jo Chung, Ryan Bertoli, and Peter D. Aplan
 Submitter: Yang Jo Chung (Staff scientist, staff clinician) email: chungya@mail.nih.gov  The ineffective hematopoiesis that is characteristic of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) suggests the presence of defective hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (HSPC). NUP98-HOXD13 (NHD13) transgenic mice recapitulate many features of human MDS such as ineffective hematopoiesis, peripheral blood cytopenias, dysplasia, and transformation to acute myeloid leukemia (AML), and have been used as a pre-clinical model for human MDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Mouse Model of Lymphomas/Leukemias: Mini-Chromosome Maintenance (Mcm) 2</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-22/</guid>
      <description>Toshihiro Matsukawa, Mianmian Yin, Ryan Bertoli, Timour Baslan, Peter D. Aplan
 Submitter: Toshihiro Matsukawa (Postdoc or fellow) email: toshihiro.matsukawa@nih.gov  DNA replicative stress is associated with malignant transformation. Mini-chromosome maintenance 2 (hereafter Mcm2) is a component of a DNA helicase complex and is required for normal DNA replication. Mice with a Cre cassette “knocked-into” the 3’UTR of the Mcm2 gene (designated Mcm2Cre) are Mcm2 hypomorphs and have decreased Mcm2 protein levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Acute Lymphoid and Myeloid Leukemia on Wild-Type Hematopoiesis in Mice</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/genetics_branch_retreat_site/abstract/submission-23/</guid>
      <description>Ryan Bertoli, Yang Jo Chung, and Peter Aplan
 Submitter: Ryan Bertoli (Student or postbac) email: RYAN.BERTOLI@NIH.GOV  Introduction: Acute lymphoid leukemia (ALL) and acute myeloid leukemia (AML) are aggressive forms of blood cancer which are difficult to treat and often fatal. These cancers hinder hematopoiesis, or the ability to produce new blood cells of diverse lineage. Leukemic cell expansion often leads to bone marrow failure, caused by a depletion of hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (HSPCs) in the marrow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>